Unite or fall.
Transformers: Rise of the Beasts is a science fiction,
adventure, action film directed by Steven Caple Jr..
When a new threat capable of destroying the entire planet emerges, Optimus Prime and
the Autobots must team up with a powerful faction known as the Maximals.
With the fate of humanity hanging in the balance, humans Noah and Elena will do whatever it
takes to help the Transformers as they engage in the ultimate battle to save Earth.
Noah Diaz, played by Anthony Ramos.
Elena Wallace, played by Dominique Fishback.
Optimus Prime (voice), played by Peter Cullen.
Optimus Primal (voice), played by Ron Perlman.
Scourge (voice), played by Peter Dinklage.
Airazor (voice), played by Michelle Yeoh.
Transformers: Rise of the Beasts is a 2023 American science fiction action film based on Hasbro's
Transformers toy line, and primarily influenced by its Beast Wars sub-franchise.
It is the seventh installment in the Transformers film
series, serving as a sequel to Bumblebee (2018).
The film is directed by Steven Caple Jr.
from a screenplay by Joby Harold, Darnell Metayer, Josh Peters, Erich
Hoeber, and Jon Hoeber, based on a story by Harold.
Michael Bay again serves as producer.
The film stars Anthony Ramos and Dominique Fishback, alongside the voices of Ron Perlman, Peter Dinklage, Michelle Yeoh, Pete Davidson, Liza Koshy, Michaela Jaé
Rodriguez, Colman Domingo, Cristo Fernández, Tongayi Chirisa, and returning franchise regulars Peter Cullen, John DiMaggio, and David Sobolov.
Set in 1994, the film follows ex-military electronics expert Noah Diaz and artifact researcher Elena Wallace as they help
the Autobots and the Maximals protect an artifact known as the Transwarp Key from the villainous Terrorcons.
A sequel was being fast-tracked by the studio after the critical and
commercial success of Bumblebee after being announced in January 2019.
Two additional films were in development the following year with one
of them being based on the Beast Wars series in 2020.
was hired as director that November later that year.
The film was officially announced months later in 2021 during a virtual
presentation as both a Bumblebee sequel and a Beast Wars film in one.
Principal photography took place from June to October 2021, with filming
locations including Los Angeles, Peru, Montreal, and New York City.
Transformers: Rise of the Beasts premiered at Marina Bay Sands in Singapore on May 27, 2023, and was
theatrically released in the United States on June 9, 2023, by Paramount Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics with many deeming
it as inferior to the preceding Bumblebee film.
It grossed a total of $441.7 million worldwide against a budget of
$195–200 million, becoming a box-office disappointment.
The film explores themes of peru, alien, end of the world, based on toy, robot.
The tone is thought_provoking.